Russell E. Harmon

Contact Information Rochester Institute of Technology PO Box 92423 Rochester, NY 14692

(585) 210-3330 russell.harmon.name russell@harmon.name

OBJECTIVE

I am looking for a three month internship to begin June. I have a current offer from Microsoft that I must respond to by October. I must be confident in an offer before I will refuse Microsoft's.

Summary

I am a person who loves to tinker. I spend the majority of my free time working on personal projects. Some of the projects I have independently worked on include the Linux kernel and the Gentoo Linux distribution. As a result, I've found that I have become very good at picking up new ideas quickly, and expanding what I already know with little more than the internet and a direction.

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology - Rochester, NY

September 2006 - Present

• Major: B.S./M.S. Computer Science

• M.S. GPA: 3.0 • Minor: Music

• Expected graduation: December 2012

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft - Boston, MA Software Development Engineering Intern

6/6/2011 - 8/26/2011 http://micorosft.com/

Worked on the "Sustained Engineering" team on the Application Virtualization product. The sustained engineering team maintains the released version of App-V. Written in C++, I worked on an as of yet unreleased feature for the App-V and Office products.

Apple Inc - Cupertino, CA Engineering Intern

6/1/2010 - 11/16/2010 http://apple.com/

Worked on the "Platform Kernel" team in the Core OS department at Apple. The majority of my work entailed work on libC, and on XNU (the Mac OS X kernel). My two major projects were (a) migrating code out of the kernel into userspace to take advantage of ASLR and (b) creation of an automated testing suite to test Mac OS X's power management on Intel processors. The ASLR work involved a great deal of collaboration between several different teams within Apple.

SafeNet Inc - Belcamp, MD Engineering Intern

June 2008 - June 2010 http://www.safenet-inc.com/

Worked on the SafeNet Management Console (SMC) on a team of 7. SMC is a web application built on Java, JBoss, Hibernate and JSF which manages high speed network encryption devices that SafeNet manufactures, including top-secret devices. Responsibilities included (a) creating requirements documents, (b) implementing requirements (IPv6, file synchronization), (c) testing and (d) fixing defects. Some of the specific tasks that were assigned while working there included transparent file synchronization between machines, implementing IPv6 support and implementing support for multiple SMC servers managing the same device (distributed devices).

CERTIFICATIONS

TECHNICAL SKILLS & Fluent Languages (a) C (b) Java (c) ZSH (d) BASH

Operating Systems (a) Linux [programming & administration] (b) Mac OS X (c) Windows Server Administration (a) LDAP (b) Kerberos (c) BIND (d) DHCPD (e) MediaWiki (f) Apache Networking (a) TCP/UDP (b) IPv4, IPv6 (c) DNS (d) DHCP (e) IPSec (f) SSL (g) X.509

Tools (a) Make (b) Autotools (c) CMake (d) LLVM (e) Regex (f) LATEX Certifications (a) Cisco Academy, with honors (terms 1 and 2) (b) A+

EXTRACURRICULAR

CSH (Computer Science House) - Network Administrator Clubs & Activities US FIRST Robotics Team 1230 - Lead programmer

http://www.csh.rit.edu/ http://www.usfirst.org/

Special ACCOMPLISHMENTS

At age 8, built my first computer. At age 10, worked my first job at City Island Computer Services. At age 12, attended my first programming class at Lehman College.